

# **Europass Curriculum Vitae**

My LinkedIN profile





### Personal information

Surname / First name

Address

Telephone

Personal Email

**Nationality** 

Date of birth

Gender

Bio

#### **Buracchi Marco**

95, Via Pier Capponi, 50132, Firenze (FI), Italy

+39 3498362954

Personal: ma.buracchi@gmail.com PEC: marco.buracchi@postecert.it

Italian

19/12/1985

Male

I'm an ICS CyberSecurity Specialist at H-ON Consulting in Prato and I attend the Short Specialisation Programme (Master I livello) in Cybersecurity at the Pisa University. I graduated in October 2018 with 110/110 cum laude at the master's degree in computer science, "resilient and secure cyber physical systems" curricula. My master thesis was on "Side-Channel Attacks and speculative execution". Before, I obtained the bachelor degree in computer science in 2015 with 110/110 cum laude.

# **Desired employment/** Occupational field

### IT/OT/IoT security, Software Development & Research

### **Education and training**

**Dates** 

02/2019 - 03/2020 (expected)

Title of qualification awarded

Principal subjects

Short Specialisation Programme - Master I livello in cybersecurity

Applied Cryptography and Access Control, Network Security & Ethical hacking, Operating Systems Security, Digital Forensics, Cyber Intelligence, Mobile and cloud security, Legal aspects of cybersecurity, Secure system configuration, device hardening and firewall management, Risk monitoring for networks and applications, Secure application development (network, mobile, cloud) Expert in security analysis of applications and IT systems, cyber attacks anal-

Occupational skills covered

ysis, big data and machine learning applied to cybersecurity.

University of Pisa, Department of Information Engineering

CNR (Consiglio Nazionale delle Ricerche) - Institute of Informatics and Telematics

Organization

Page 1 / 4 - Curriculum vitæ of Buracchi Marco For more informations go to https://it.linkedin.com/in/marco-buracchi-287074b2 © European Union, 2002-2016.

ISCED/EQF level

**Dates** 

7

11/2018 - 07/2019

Title of qualification awarded

CISCO Cybersecurity Scholarship Italy

Certification obtained

Introduction to cybersecurity (11-2018), Cybersecurity essential (01-2019), In-

troduction to Packet Tracer (02-2019).

Organization

CISCO networking academy

**Dates** 

01/10/2015 - 12/10/2018

Title of qualification awarded

Master's degree in Resilient and Secure Cyber Physical Systems

Principal

Security engineering, Security and network management, Distributed pro-

subjects/Occupational skills covered gramming for IoT, Multivariate analysis and statistical learning, Coding theory and computer security, Advanced techniques (and tools) for software development, Advanced topics in programming languages, Computer forensics, Models of sequential and concurrent systems, Quantitative analysis of systems, Real-time and critical systems, Systems modeling for verification, Advanced numerical analysis

Organization Final grade University of Florence, Faculty of Maths, Physics and Natural Sciences

110/110 cum laude

ISCED/EQF level 7

**Dates** 

08/08/2017 - 12/08/2017

Title of qualification awarded

Cornell, Maryland, Max Planck pre-doctoral research school

Principal

Security and privacy, social systems, distributed systems, machine learning, programming languages, and verification

subjects/Occupational skills covered

Max Planck institute for software systems, Cornell University, University of

Organization

Maryland

**Dates** 

01/10/2012 - 09/10/2015

Title of qualification awarded

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science.

Organization Final grade University of Florence, Faculty of Maths, Physics and Natural Sciences

110/110 cum laude

ISCED/EQF level

6

Work experiences

**Dates** 13/02/2020 - now

Occupation or position held

ICS CyberSecurity Specialist

Main activities

Cybersecurity consultancy applied to the OT / IACS world in accordance with the processes and requirements of the IEC 62443 standard, development of services and techniques for the analysis of customer systems in terms of infrastructure and vulnerability, risk analysis, development of specific technical reports, procedures, the choice of necessary HW and SW and the setting up of a new dedicated laboratory. Identifying and coordinating a team of technicians dedicated to the service.

**Employer** 

H-ON consulting, Via Lepanto, 23, 59100 Prato PO

Type of business or sector

ICS CyberSecurity

Dates 01/10/2019 - now

Occupation or position held | Junior Security Engineer

Main activities Vulnerability assessment, penetration testing, research and development.

**Employer** 

Florence Consulting Group, Via L. Lama, 23, 50019 Sesto Fiorentino Fl

Dates 28/11/2018 - 31/08/2019

Occupation or position held | Private tutor

Main activities One-on-one in-house tutoring for middle-school, high-scool and university stu-

dents.

Employer | Centro didattico Matemagia - Via Baracca 166, Firenze

Type of business or sector | Private education

Dates 01/04/2015 - 01/10/2016

Occupation or position held Research helper

Main activities and responsibilities

I took part in AMADEOS project (Architecture for Multi-criticality Agile Dependable Evolutionary Open System-of-Systems) funded under the European Commission's FP7, supporting research in definition, implementation and

time in the smart grid and smart cities. http://amadeos-project.eu/

evaluation of mechanisms and solutions for the resilient management of the

Employer Prof. Andrea Bondavalli, Resilient Computing Lab, Università di Firenze

Type of business or sector Research and experimentation of dependable architectures and systems

Dates 01/05/2006 - 01/09/2012

Main activities AutoCAD drawing, CNC programming and cutting (laser cutting, machining

center, wire EDM)

Name and address of Nuova 230AR, Arezzo, Italy (01/05/2006 - 01/05/2008)

employer | Gabry packing, Arezzo, Italy (01/05/2008 - 01/09/2012)

Type of business or sector | Manufacturing industry

Dates 01/09/2004 - 01/05/2006

Occupation or position held | Technical employee

responsibilities grams developer

Employer | Emmedi srl, Arezzo, Italy

Type of business or sector | Manufacturing industry

# Personal skills and competences

Mother tongue Other language(s)

Self-assessment European level<sup>(\*)</sup>

**English** 

### Italian

Understanding		Speaking		Writing
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C1 Proficient user				

<sup>(\*)</sup> Common European Framework of Reference (CEF) level

# Computer skills and competences

Very good computer skills, learned as self-taught and through the University. Good knowledge in the use of Kali Linux OS and various IT security and cyber intelligence tools (among the best known: Metasploit, OpenVAS, Nessus, Legion, Maltego). High expertise with many tools such as Apache NiFi, ElasticSearch, Kibana, Maven, Github, virtualization tools, Docker, test-framework.

Artistic skills and competences

I studied piano at conservatoire for 4 years. I can play guitar. I love skiing and I'm a futsal goalkeeper for more than 10 years

Driving licence(s)

Driver's license (Italian Republic, full European validity), category A (motorcycle owner) and B (car owner).

## **Additional informations**

#### References

Prof. Michele Boreale, University of Florence, Italy, michele.boreale(AT)unifi.it;

Prof. Rosario Pugliese, University of Florence, Italy, rosario.pugliese(AT)unifi.it;

### **Personal interests**

IT security, Technology, Mathematics, Physics and Science in general. Books, Music and all kind of sports. Travelling around the world.

I hereby authorize the processing of the personal data contained in this CV in compliance with the Italian Personal Data Protection Code (Legislative Decree no. 196 of 30 June 2003 and GDPR 679/16 art.13)

Signature: